好了  请你们吃完饭了
Okay, I've fed you.
有谁想看篮球赛啊
Now, who's ready to watch some basketball?
我为什么在看你
Why am I looking at you?
不知道
I don't know.
不像你  我看穿着短裤
Unlike you, I don't need a reason
到处跑的哥们儿不需要理由
to watch a bunch of guys run around in shorts.
你已经毁了我的奥运会跳水比赛
Don't ruin this for me like you did
别又毁了篮球
with Olympic diving.
-小卡呢  -录下来吧
- Cam?   - Recording it.
米奇和我要带艾丽克斯和曼尼去看美术展
Mitch and I are taking Alex and Manny to an art exhibit.
但当然了  大家都可以一起去
But, of course, everybody is welcome to join.
那是战后抽象表现主义的回顾展
It's a retrospective on post-war abstract expressionism.
等等  学校要求的吗
Wait. For school?
不是  是生活所需
No, for life.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
我都不知道我们在那场"战后"
I don't even know who we fought
是跟谁打的
in the post war.
早就告诉你开一辆车就够了
Told you one car was enough.
看来只有我们两个啦
Looks like it's just the two amigos.
海莉呢
Haley?
真抱歉我吃饱了就要走  外公
Oh, sorry to brunch and bail, grandpa,
但我有个约会
but I've got a date.
跟谁啊
Uh, with whom?
我在学校认识的帅哥
A gorgeous guy I met at school.
是同学还是扫教室的
Ooh, goes there or cleans there?
老妈
Mom.
回答她的问题
Answer the question.
大家都要走了吗
So everyone's leaving?
不  我  我不走啊
No, I'm -- I'm not.
早知道就不请你们吃上好的培根了
I wish I had known this before I served the good bacon.
你又没请大家吃上好的培根
You did not serve the good bacon.
你不是要去买一条小裙子吗
Don't you have a tiny dress to buy?
是啊  没错
Yes, we do!
我们请歌洛莉亚带莉莉
We asked Gloria to take Lily
去买一条花童礼裙
to pick out her flower-girl dress.
没错  我们显然无法遵循所有婚礼传统
Yeah, we're clearly not following every wedding tradition,
但绝对会有一条裙子是我们
but there will damn sure be one dress
[西方婚礼中新郎到婚礼当天才可以见到新娘穿婚纱]
两个新郎到婚礼当天才能见到的
the grooms don't see until the big day.
我们也请克莱尔一起去
And we also asked Claire to go
因为我们认为她的理性
because we thought her sensible style
能与歌洛莉亚的豪放互补
nicely complements Gloria's flair.
这样莉莉就不会看起来太过...
That way Lily doesn't end up looking too...
或者太过...
or too...
■
m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译：小饭  四方虾  王大可  冰蓝
时间轴：浓子   校对：olivia_xuxu   后期&总监：瓜瓜
摩  登
家  庭
第五季 第十七集
我的乖儿子
There's my boy.
我知道你在跟乔说话
I know you're talking to Joe,
不过听到这话还是很开心
but that still feels really good to hear.
好了  下班了哦
Okay, clocking out.
安迪  如果你愿意的话
You know, Andy, if you want,
你可以留下来看比赛
you can stay and watch the game.
否则  我就得一个人看了
Otherwise, I'll just be here by myself.
我在这儿呢
I'm right here.
我也很想看  普先生
I-I'd love to, Mr. P,
但我得去想想送我女友什么周年礼物
but I got to come up with an anniversary gift for my girlfriend.
我每年都为她准备不同的礼物
I make her something different every year,
比如剪贴本  或漂亮的围巾
like a scrapbook or a nice scarf.
今年
This year,
我想也许我可以为她烤些香蕉面包
I was thinking maybe I could bake her some banana bread.
我可是香蕉面包之王
Ohh, I am the king of banana bread.
你知道我的秘诀吗
You know my secret?
别放坚果
No nuts.
[No nuts 双关: 没有睾丸]
这不是什么秘密
Not such a secret.
我以前也总给克莱尔做东西
I used to make stuff for Claire all the time.
我相信是我的手艺牢牢锁住了她的心
Pretty sure my artistry is what locked her down.
今年我要搞点特别的
I got to make this year's special.
她在海岸警卫队
With her in the coast guard,
我都没什么机会去看她
I, like, hardly ever get to see her.
我刚刚想到
Well, this is just off the dome,
送她一段好玩的视频怎么样
but, uh, maybe send her a fun video?
她确实很喜欢《摇滚年代》
Ooh, she does love "Rock of Ages."
或者你也可以录一段自己的视频
Or you could make your own video --
搞点专属浪漫
something romantic and personal
有真正制作价值的
with real production value.
我家里有些相当不错的设备
I got some pretty choice equipment back at the house.
我很乐意帮你
I'd be happy to help.
-真的吗  -当然了
- Would you really? - Yeah!
太好了
Yes!
太棒了  马上开工
Great! Let's do it!
卢克  伙计  我晚点来接你
Luke, buddy, I'll pick you up later.
然后一起去看轮子
We can go check out some wheels.
[wheels还有车的意思]
我以为你要留下来看比赛呢
I thought you were gonna stay and watch the game.
我就知道你爱我
I knew you loved me.
出去
Get out!
走吧
Come on.
看轮子  怎么  你已经开始看车了吗
Wheels? What, are you looking at cars already?
是陶轮
Pottery wheels.
我得选个春季选修课
I have to pick a spring elective,
老爸认为我该选陶艺
and dad thinks I should take ceramics
因为会有很多女孩选
'cause lots of girls do.
你知道大多数姑娘不喜欢什么吗
You know what a lot of girls don't do?
修陶艺课的男生
Guys who take ceramics.
你们学校有木工场吗
You got a wood shop at your school?
我不会制造东西啊
I can't really build stuff.
我只会破坏  然后道歉
I mostly take apart and apologize.
你得学会制造东西才行
You got to know how to build things.
我会制造悬念
I can build suspense.
怎么制造
How?
你看
Well, get this.
去车库  马上
Garage. Now.
婚纱店是什么
What's a bridal store?
那里有你见过最漂亮的裙子
It's a place with the most wonderful dresses that you have ever seen.
我们要给你挑一条最完美的
We're gonna get you the perfect one
哪怕花上一天时间
even if it takes us all day.
找到了
Found it.
不  亲爱的  那是戏服
Oh, no, sweetie. That's a costume.
你不能穿着戏服参加婚礼
You can't wear a costume to a wedding.
为什么不行  贝拉是个公主
Why not? Belle's a princess.
她面对的是野兽
She faced the beast.
她勇敢反抗市民
She stood up to the townspeople.
那你做了什么呢
What have you done?
我  成功把车停进了那个
I...got us into that tiny,
小小的停车位上
little parking spot.
漂亮的裙子不止公主裙一种
Princess dresses are not the only pretty dresses.
我想当公主
I want to be a princess.
I want to be a princess!
别再说了
Stop that right now.
你的爸爸们想让你买一条花童礼裙
Your dads want you to have a flower-girl dress,
所以我们就要给你买一条花童礼裙
and that's what we're going to get you.
走吧
So march.
停车位上面标着"小车型专用"
It was...it was marked "Compact" and --
而我们开的是面包车  所以
and we're driving a minivan, so...
感谢你们请我们来
Hey, thanks for inviting us to this.
别客气
Oh, no problem.
我很吃惊  我们四人组居然没有
You know, I'm surprised that this particular foursome
经常一起出来  考虑到
doesn't hang out more often, considering --
这家里只有我们受过教育吗
We're the cultured ones in the family?
我不会这么说的
I wouldn't say that.
如果不是跟你们一起的话
Outside of this group.
你知道你爸爸
Did you know your father
去杂货店买书的事情吗
actually goes to the grocery store to buy books?
我知道  是啊
I did know that, yeah.
我还知道让我姐姐睡觉的
I also know that the best way
最好办法就是
to get my sister to fall asleep is to --
给她看有字幕的电影
Show her a movie with subtitles.
晚安  妈妈[法语]
Bonne nuit, mama.
我们应该庆幸且感激
We should be nice and grateful
我们今天能够在这个私人画廊
that we have this day to spend together
一起度过美好时光
in our own private salon.
[salon有画廊和美发沙龙两个意思]
别跟我妈说那话
Don't tell my mom that.
她会跳出来说要染头发
She'll show up and ask to get her roots done.
-曼尼  -那是真的  是真的
- Manny! - That's true. It's true.
谢谢  曼尼
Thanks, manny.
我好期待这场展览
I am so excited for this exhibit.
我超级崇拜康丁斯基
I'm such an admirer of Kandinsky.
他可是被誉为
You know, he was credited
创作真正意义上抽象作品的第一人啊
with painting the first truly abstract work.
是吗
Is that so?
说实话  跟这三个家伙
To be honest, I was a little nervous
一起出来  我有点紧张
about holding my own with those three,
所以我做了些关于康丁斯基的功课
so I did a little boning up on Kandinsky.
反正多记几个知识点是不会错的
Figured it couldn't hurt to have a few facts in my pocket.
我的后备计划是上手摸展品然后被赶出去
My backup plan was to touch a painting and get thrown out.
女士  你好  打扰一下
Miss, hi. Excuse me.
可以告诉我们康丁斯基的画展在哪里吗
Can you tell us where the Kandinsky exhibit is?
卫斯理・康丁斯基
You know, Wassily Kandinsky?
生于莫斯科  一个茶商的儿子
Born in Moscow, son of a tea merchant?
抱歉  那场画展是临时的
I'm sorry. That exhibit was temporary.
已经结束了
It's closed.
什么
What?
不是吧
No.
我喜欢这幅马蒂斯的画
Oh, I love this Matisse.
这是他最后的作品之一
You know this is one of his final works.
他健康状况恶化使他开始探索剪纸
His failing health led to his exploration of paper cutouts.
是啊  我记得他称之为"用剪刀作画"
Ah, yes. I believe he called it "Painting with scissors."
而且他跟毕加索生活在同一时代
And he was also a contemporary of Picasso.
你完全能看出他们是如何影响彼此的
You can definitely see how they influenced each other.
是吧  小卡
Right, Cam?
这画一下让我想起了...
Uh, well, you know, it really reminds me...
康丁斯基
Of, uh, Kandinsky.
为什么
How so?
看起来不大一样  但材质很相似
Well, not so much in look, more in texture.
不  小卡
No, no, Cam!
先生  请不要碰画作
No, please, sir, don't touch the art.
抱歉  我马上离开这里
I'm sorry. I'll leave the premises.
不  没关系
No, it's -- it's fine.
您后退几步就行了
Just take a few steps back.
贝丝  我愿意游过满是鲨鱼的深海
Beth, I would swim the deepest, sharkiest oceans
来和你在一起
to be with you.
你们在干什么
What are you doing?
停拍
Cut!
这样就穿帮了
Well, now we have a blooper reel.
我们在为安迪的女友拍视频情书
We're making a video love letter for Andy's girlfriend.
你爸爸用他的电脑来设置很棒的背景
Your dad uses his computer to put in cool backgrounds
而我表演为了和她在一起
while I act out all the things that
我愿意做的事
I would do to be with her,
比如游过深海  或者爬山
like swim an ocean or climb a mountain.
不如你像个正常人一样
Ooh, how about you buy a plane ticket
买机票去看她啊
and visit her like a normal person?
我也想啊  但她忙于海岸警卫队的工作
I would, but the coast guard keeps her really busy.
闭上眼  她喜欢吗
Eyes. Does she like it?
40人的队伍里只有两个女生和她聊天
She's probably so lonely with only two other women
她一定感觉十分孤单
to talk to in her whole 40-person unit.
所以你是说你女朋友
So you're saying it's just your girlfriend
和36个型男在一起吗
and 36 super in-shape dudes?
是37个  而且不是你想的那样
37. And it's not what you think.
海岸警卫队非常不赞成队内恋爱
The coast guard seriously frowns on fraternizing.
这是禁止的
It's forbidden.
禁果更甜好吗
That doesn't make it hot.
你的脸上也喷到了一点
Oh, I got some on your face.
你会发光的
You're gonna shine.
我去拿我的  克莱尔的粉饼
I'll go get some of my -- Claire's powder.
我的克莱尔  她是我妻子
My Claire. She's my wife.
你不是要去约会的吗
I thought you had a date to go on.
是啊
I do.
他什么时候来啊
When's he gonna get here?
快了吧
Whenever he does.
他也就晚了几分钟
He's just, like, a few minutes late.
真遗憾
I'm sorry.
真是无礼
That is so rude.
真正的男人会考虑到你的时间的
A real man would be more considerate of your time.
是啊
You're right.
所以每年《人物》杂志
That's why every year People magazine
都提名"最贴心"的男人
names the "Consideratest" man alive.
好吧  随你怎么取笑我
Oh, man, you can make fun of me all you want,
但你长大后
but when you grow up,
就会知道哪些品质能塑造一个真正的男人
you'll see what qualities make up a real man.
[make up也有化妆的意思]
有人说要化妆吗
Someone say "Makeup"?
是我
I did.
好了  开始吧
All right, here we go.
这样好多了
Oh, yeah. Much better.
我要在这下面打造阴影
You know what? I think I'm gonna shadow down here.
歌洛莉亚  你会爱上这条裙子的
Gloria, you are gonna love this one.
我觉得我们终于找到了最完美的裙子
I think we have finally found the perfect dress.
瞧瞧
Ta-da.
是不错啦  但我不喜欢蝴蝶结
It's nice, but I don't like the bow.
再试几件吧
Let's try more.
我们已经试了六条裙子
We've tried on six dresses already.
她对这条没意见  对吧  莉莉
She's fine with this. Right, Lily?
我无所谓
I don't care.
瞧  她很喜欢  搞定
See? She loves it. Done.
去试试有蕾丝花边的
Go try the lace one.
没搞错吧
Seriously?
真是没完没了啊
This is endless.
你为什么要拖延啊
Why are you dragging this out?
因为我们还没找到合适的裙子
Because we haven't found the right dress.
你肯定不是这么烂的顾客吧
You have got to be a better shopper than this.
我看见过你开着车就买了三件衣服
I have seen you buy three outfits while driving a car.
拜托  这很好玩啊
Come on. It's fun.
我没有女儿
I don't have any daughters.
我能买的只有男士晚礼服
All I get to buy is tuxedos,
它们看起来都一样
and they all look the same.
但是别告诉曼尼
But don't tell Manny that
因为我不想再听他讲晚礼服了
because I don't want to hear another lecture.
真有趣
It's funny.
我从来没关心过这种东西
I have never cared about any of this stuff.
我嫁给菲尔时都没有穿婚纱
I didn't even wear a wedding dress when I married Phil.
甚至都没有试穿过
Never even tried one on.
放松点  你看见我身后
Easy. That is the reaction
有个持枪男子才该是这种反应好吗
for when there's a man behind me with a gun.
我只是说我不在乎婚纱
All I said is I don't care about wedding dresses.
因为你没穿过
Because you've never been in one.
我要给你挑一件试穿
I'm gonna pick some for you to try.
不要了  没必要
Okay, no, no. No need.
来吧  会很漂亮的
Come on, you'll feel beautiful.
试穿后你就可以换回你的  男士服装
Then you can go back to your...boy clothes.
这件衬衫是给卢克买的  没法退
I bought this shirt for Luke and I couldn't return it.
我可没有一整天时间来试穿裙子
And I don't have all day to try on dresses.
我就有吗
Oh, and I do?
这对我来说会很好玩的
It'll be fun for me.
你是我的继女
You're my stepdaughter.
我比你大
I'm older than you.
瞧瞧  已经很好玩了
You see? It's already fun.
先来做一个简单的工具箱
We're gonna start by building a simple toolbox.
首先我教你怎么切割木头
First, I'm gonna show you how to cut the wood.
我知道这对你来说太过高深  小家伙
I know you're a little young for this, goober.
尽量吸收吧
Try to soak it all up.
这是什么
What's this thing?
台钳
A table vise.
台钳  台
Table vise, ta--
不
No.
我已经和米奇尔经历过这种事了
I already went through this with Mitchell.
我们来这里就是要预防那种事发生
That's what we're here to prevent.
你爸爸没教你这些吗
Didn't your dad teach you any of this stuff?
他说你唯一需要的工具就是幽默感
He says the only tool you need is a sense of humor.
如果你有个很搞笑的敲门笑话
'Cause who needs the jaws of life
那还需要什么救生颚啊
if you have a good knock-knock joke?
卢克  去那边拿护目镜
Luke, grab the goggles over there, please.
用心点
And try to pay attention.
我们测量两次
We measure twice,
切割一次
and we cut once.
外公  你能举起180磅的杠铃吗
Hey, grandpa, can you bench 180 pounds?
我说了用心点
I just said pay attention.
加上杆子其实有205磅
And that's actually 205 with the bar.
我一会儿举给你看
I'll lift that for you later.
我知道你心里还挂念着那个
I can see you're not gonna let up about that.
没有啦
Eh, I'm okay.
瞧瞧我的
Spot me.
如果大事不妙
Now, if this thing goes south,
你要打给911
I want you to call 911
告诉乔他的老爸死得光荣
and tell Joe his old man died as he lived --
救了一火车人
saving a trainload of people.
好了  这几下够了
All right. That's enough for now.
告诉我你对女人的一切了解
Tell me everything you know about women.
是啊  最后一句
Yeah, that last thing.
有趣  有趣  有趣
Funny. Funny. Funny.
我一定没跟上你们
I must be a little behind you guys.
他说的话
His words.
你感受到发生的事了吗
Do you feel what's happening here?
-我觉得好痛  -不是
- I feel pinching. - No.
我是这个超级组合里的薄弱环节
I'm the weak link of this super group.
他们知道  我也知道
They know it and I know it.
我们都在一大堆人中还没关系
It's fine when we're all in a big group,
但是一旦我们单独相处
but once we're separated from the herd,
我就露马脚了
the hooves come out.
你说的应该是爪子吧
Don't you mean "Claws"?
有爪子的动物不成"堆"活动  米奇尔
Clawed animals don't travel in herds, Mitchell.
得用"群"称呼
Packs, flocks, and prides.
我们为什么不能去农场
Why can't we be on a farm?
我会让你们觉得相形见绌的
I'd make you all look like such idiots.
知道吗
You know what?
我就去外面等着好了
I'm just gonna wait outside.
不  小卡  别这样
Wh-- no. Cam, come on.
你这样太蠢了
You're being silly.
老实说
To be perfectly honest,
我真的需要小卡留下来
I-I really needed Cam to stay.
他一走
The minute he goes,
我就成笨蛋了
I'm the dumb one.
我上过一次艺术史课
I-I took an art history class once,
但那只是为了看一群赤裸的意大利男人
but that was just to look at naked Italian dudes, so...
记住
Remember now,
你身处零度以下的气温中
you're in subzero temperatures.
唯一让你觉得温暖的
The only thing keeping you warm
就是激情燃烧的热度
is the heat of your fiery passion.
开始
And...go!
我美丽的贝丝
My beautiful Beth --
-再冷一点  -我美美美丽的贝贝丝
- Colder! - My b-b-beautiful B-Beth.
-再冷一点  -贝贝贝贝...
- Colder! - B-B-B-B--
太冷了
That's too cold.
贝贝贝丝
B-B-Beth!
就是这样
Now we're talking!
我觉得你好美
You're so beautiful to me!
太棒了
Yes!
我为什么这么想帮安迪
Why am I so intent on helping Andy?
我喜欢拍电影和爱情
I love filmmaking and I love love.
你可以说我喜欢拍摄爱情[在电影里做爱]
I guess you could say I enjoy making love on film,
现在我不用自己做了
and now I don't have to do it by myself.
贝丝  我从远方说想你
Beth, this is my long way of saying I miss you.
不是我说  这太别扭了
Th-- uh. You know, this is weird.
我都不知道该看哪里
I don't really know where to look.
不  不别扭
No, it's not weird.
深情地看着我的双眼感动我
J-just look deep into my eyes and sweep me off my feet.
好吧
All right.
亲爱的
Honey...
没错  这太别扭了
Yeah, that's weird.
是的
It is. Yeah.
海莉  亲爱的  帮帮我们吧
Haley, honey, can you help us?
没人帮得了你们
I don't think anyone can.
让安迪给你公主抱
Just let Andy hold you "Officer and a gentleman" style,
我在电脑上把贝丝的脸叠加在你脸上
and I'll superimpose Beth's face over yours on the computer.
这太扯了
That's insane.
我知道  我用这个无所不能
I know. I can do anything with this.
要是她觉得别扭
If she's not comfortable
告诉你们吧
You know what, guys?
这事真的太可悲了
This whole thing is really sad and pathetic.
女孩们都不喜欢男人这么主动
No girl wants a guy that tries this hard.
要是我收到这么个视频
If I got this video,
我会报警的
I'd call the police.
有的女孩会喜欢对她们好的男人
Some girls actually like guys who are nice to them.
有的女孩会喜欢36个那样的男人
Some girls like 36 of them.
有37个
There's 37 of them!
好了  就要这种激情
Okay, this is passion.
可以利用起来
We can use it.
安迪  抱她起来
Andy, pick her up.
来吧  把这条搞定
All right, let's just get this over with.
天啊  他真的把我抱起来了  爸爸
Oh, my gosh, he's actually picking me up! Dad!
马上就好
It's just for a minute.
现在注视着对方
Now lock eyes and...
开拍
Action.
亲爱的  我从远方说想你
Honey, this is my long way of saying I miss you.
我不必爬上高山
I don't have to climb a mountain
不必远过重洋去见你
or swim an ocean to be with you,
因为你一直在我身边
'cause you're always with me--
在我的脑海里
in my thoughts,
我的梦里
my dreams...
我的心里
my heart.
我值得我用尽所有的能力去爱你
You deserve more than I could possibly ever give you,
可你就是我的全部
but everything I have is yours.
我爱你
I love you.
停
Cut!
太美了
That was beautiful.
我真的感觉到了
I really felt that one.
你感觉到了吗
Did you feel that one?
我什么都没感觉到
No, I didn't feel anything.
我在问安迪
I was talking to Andy.
我知道  放我下来  变态
I know! Put me down, freak!
真让我怀念啦啦队的日子
That really takes me back to my cheerleading days.
一个承受着那么多痛苦的人
How could a guy with so much pain
是如何创作出这么充满希望的作品的
create such hopeful imagery?
要是我妈患上肺病晚期
I certainly couldn't paint like that
我可画不出来这样的作品
if my mother was dying of consumption.
她上次感冒
The last time she had a cold,
我连茶几的花都摆不好
I could barely arrange the flowers on the front table.
你知道我觉得什么最有意思吗
You know what I found so interesting?
是第一幅画和最后一幅
Was that the first painting and the last painting
简直太像了
were so similar,
我认为那是有意图的
and I think that that was intentional,
是对永恒人生的诠释
a comment on the perpetual motion of life.
第一幅就是最后一幅
The first painting was the last painting.
我们走了一圈
We walked in a circle.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
我要去找小卡
So...you know, I'm gonna go check on Cam
他一个人呆了很久了
because he's been alone f-for quite some time.
他可能在摸哪幅画呢
And, you know, he's probably touching a painting.
别  别走啊
N-no, don't go!
我们正聊得高兴呢
We're having such a good time.
就剩我们两个了
I guess it's just you and me now.
小卡走了没什么
It was okay when Cam left
我还有米奇尔这个笨蛋垫底
and passed the dunce cap to Mitchell,
可他走了的话
but with him gone,
就轮到我了
it went to me.
要是卢克在就好了
What I would've given to have Luke there.
卢克啊
Ah, Luke.
又可人又够蠢
Sweet as custard and just as smart.
搞定了
And presto.
太感谢了  邓菲先生
Thank you so much, Mr. Dunphy.
真不知道怎么感谢你
I wish I could repay you somehow.
别客气  下次见到你女朋友
Nah. Next time you're with your girlfriend,
想着我就好
just think of me.
没问题
Done.
走了
Later.
那是谁啊
Who's that?
我的约会对象
My date.
你约的午饭吗  这都5点了
Your lunch date? It's 5:00.
他睡过了
He fell asleep.
可他一睡醒就给我发短信了
But he texted me right when he woke up.
你觉得他休息够了吗
Well, then, you'd think he'd be well-rested enough
他连过来敲门的力气都没有
to walk to the front door.
男人鸣笛来鼓舞士气
Yeah, a gentleman honks to support the troops,
可不是召唤女朋友
not summon his girlfriend.
虽然我女朋友就是军人
Although my girlfriend is a troop,
所以对我来说  两者有点分不清
so in my case, it's a little confusing.
天呐  真唠叨
Oh, my god, it's still talking.
因为他知道你没有受到尊重
Because it knows you're not being respected.
-谢谢  -别客气
- Thank you.  - You bet.
你们不懂真实世界里的
Ugh. You guys don't understand how dating works
约会是怎样的
in the real world.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
看看安迪今天为贝丝做的一切
Look at everything Andy did for Beth today.
我活着就是为了让她高兴
I just live my life to make her happy.
我要去把这个交给邮差
I'm gonna give this to the mailman
他会把它给海岸警卫队
who's gonna give it to the coast guard,
明天这个时候
and by this time tomorrow,
海岸警卫队的某个人
someone in the coast guard's
会把它交给我女朋友
gonna be giving it to my girlfriend.
能想象她看到这个时
Can you imagine the smile on her face
挂在脸上的笑容吗
when she takes it all in?
我要走了  你俩好好回味吧
Okay, I'm gonna go while you two replay that in your minds.
天呐
Oh, my gosh.
你想重演《地心引力》吗
Would you like to re-enact "Gravity"?
好啊  我演桑德拉・布洛克
Yes. Sandra Bullock!
该死
Dang it!
不错  抢得够快
Good call. That was quick.
我等了你一个下午就这待遇吗
That's what I get after I waited for you all afternoon?
你真美
Uh...you look good?
这我知道
I know that.
你几个小时前就该来接我了
You were supposed to pick me up hours ago.
你可是我醒了以后  第一个
You were, like, the first or second person
或第二个发短信的人
I texted after I woke up.
真感人
Aww! That's so sweet.
你想没想过要走到门前去敲门啊
Did it even occur to you who comes to the door?
还要走到门前
Comes to the door?
做个绅士
A gentleman.
你可以至少帮我开下车门吗
Could you at least open the car door for me?
我们能走了吗
Now can we go?
够了
You know what?
去再睡一觉吧
Go take another nap.
我宁可等一个
I'd rather wait for someone
愿意为我穿越风雪
who'd walk through a blizzard for me
而且鸣笛只为了鼓舞士气的人
and only honks to support the troops!
我没明白你的意思
I don't understand you.
我也不明白
Neither do i!
克莱尔  你太美了
Claire, you look beautiful.
你真闪耀
You're glowing.
我不闪耀
I'm not glowing.
我是在冒汗
I'm sweating.
拜托
Come on.
看着镜子里的自己
Look at yourself in the mirror.
别告诉我你没有感到高贵而特别
Don't tell me that you don't feel gorgeous and special.
你说得对
You're right.
我在发光
I am radiant.
我就好像是
Oh, it's like I'm in a...
在童话或者梦里
in a fairy tale or a dream.
说谎
Lies!
你是装出来的
You're faking it.
抱歉
Well, I'm sorry!
想想是谁把我养大的
Look who raised me.
我是我爸的女儿
I am my father's daughter...
还兼任半个儿子
and also kind of his son.
那件衬衫不是买给卢克的
And I lied about that being Luke's shirt.
我给自己买了三种颜色的
I bought it for myself in three colors.
我就是想配合你而已  歌洛莉亚
I am trying to help you out here, Gloria,
可这不是我
But this just isn't me.
你确实帮了我
You did help me.
真庆幸我没有女儿
I am glad I didn't have daughters.
至少我带曼尼逛街时
You know, at least when I take Manny shopping,
我们一天都会很愉快
we make a day of it.
我都不用让他转动身体
I don't even have to ask him to twirl
因为他会主动转起来
because he just does it.
走了  莉莉
Vamos, Lily!
莉莉
Lily?
-莉莉  -莉莉
- Lily? - Lily?
她是不是  没有
Is she-- no.
没有吗  她走了  她走了
No? She's gone. She's gone.
-莉莉  -等等  等等
- Lily! - Wait. Wait.
莉莉  莉莉  莉莉
Lily! Lily! Lily! Lily!
别走  裙子
No, the dress!
-莉莉  -莉莉
- Lily? - Lily?
等等  等等  等等
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
我穿高跟鞋跑不动
I can't run in these shoes!
现在你想穿男孩子的鞋了吧
I bet you wish you had boy shoes now, huh?
莉莉
Lily?
-克莱尔  等一下  -怎么了
- Claire, stop! - What?
-看  -我的天
- Look! - Oh, my god.
好的  跑  跑起来  快点
Okay, run, run. Come on. Come on!
她看起来好开心
She looks so happy.
是啊
She does.
她真的好开心
Oh, she really does.
他们一定会杀了我们
They're gonna kill us.
什么样的公主
What sort of princess?
就是那个和野兽跳舞
The kind that dances with beasts
[加斯顿: 美女与野兽中的镇上土豪]
不嫁给加斯顿的美女
and won't marry Gaston.
-真的吗  -怎么了
- Really? - What?
她只喜欢这一件
It's the only dress she likes.
莉莉想在婚礼上打扮成贝尔
Lily wants to come to the wedding as Belle.
也说得通
Makes sense.
她在胡娇的家宴上穿成了小探险家多拉
She went to Pepper's Seder as Dora the explorer.
好吧
I-it's fine.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
是的  没事
Yes. Yes.
只要她开心就好
A-As long as she's happy.
在男同性恋婚礼上阻止别人成为
A gay wedding is hardly the place to stop someone
她想成为的样子确实不太合适
from being who they want to be.
他们说可以
They said it's fine.
我终于开心啦
Yay! I'm finally happy!
怎么了
What?
我看到你转动身体了
I saw you twirl.
我才没有
Oh, I did not.
你有
Yes, you did.
多漂亮的小姑娘啊
Such a pretty girl.
闭嘴
Shut up.
你才是姑娘
You're a girl.
我们的女儿怎么样了
How about that daughter of ours?
她跟着自己的心情走了吧
She marches to the beat of her own drum, huh?
是啊
Yeah. Exactly.
所以  为什么我们要那么在意
S-so, why are we so concerned
两个书呆子怎么看我们
what two nerdy teenagers think of us?
真正的大智慧
Isn't the true mark of intelligence
不就是承认自己不知道什么吗
being able to admit what you don't know?
小声点  曼尼过来了
Shh. Here comes Manny.
天哪  他没听到我说的吧
Oh, my god. Did he hear me?
伙计们
Hey, guys.
没什么
Nothin'.
你来这里干什么
Hey, what are you doing out here?
是你们两个今天邀请我们来的
You guys invited us so we could spend the day together.
但你们在这里
It felt wrong that you two are out here
只有我和艾丽克斯在里面怪怪的
and I was in there all alone with Alex.
跟不上她的节奏了  对吧
Couldn't keep up, could you?
她什么都知道
She knows everything.
她把一个讲解员都弄哭了
She made a docent cry.
没关系  我们也是假装懂的
It's okay. We're faking it, too.
是吧
Well, duh.
你们在这里啊
There you guys are.
没什么
Nothin'.
我们正要回去呢
Uh, we were just headed back in.
是啊  我们就在外面透透气
Yeah, I'm getting a second wind.
不  不  没关系
Oh, no, no, no. That's okay.
不如我们去找点东西吃吧
Uh, what do you say we go check out some food trucks?
真的吗
Really?
如果你们很想进去我也可以
I'll go back in if you guys want,
但我真的很饿
but I'm actually really hungry.
-随你便  -你说了算
- Yeah, whatever you want.  - Okay, well, whatever you need,
好吧  谢谢你们
Yeah.Thanks, guys.
要我说实话
If I'm being honest,
我必须得出来了
I had to get out of there.
我在那装了一整天傻真是太累了
I was exhausted from having to dumb it down all day.
真的吗  脖子
Really? The neck?
是啊  脖子上一吻  什么门都能开
Yeah, a kiss on the neck opens all kinds of doors.
最后一个
Last one.
干得好  小冠军
Great job, champ.
谁说你什么都做不出来的
Who said you can't build anything?
我爸爸  警察  医生
My dad, the police, a doctor.
你有天分
You got a gift.
相信我  学点工科
Trust me. Take shop.
我想我会的
I think I'm gonna.
你怎么会知道这么多事情呢
Hey, how'd you get to know so much about everything?
大多是我爸爸教我的
From my dad, mostly.
他教我如何用电钻
He taught me how to use a drill,
如何换轮胎
change a tire,
如何在兄弟叫你帮忙搬家的时候装病
fake an injury when a buddy asks you to help him move.
所有男人的生活技能
Everything a man needs to get by.
我很高兴我这些技能能传下去
I'm just glad I have someone to pass it on to.
你有曼尼啊
You've got Manny.
曼尼认识我的时候基本已经定型了
Manny came to me kind of fully cooked.
培养米奇尔的时候我还太年轻
And I was an idiot with Mitchell,
再等这个家伙长大
and by the time this guy gets old enough,
谁知道我还能记得些什么
who knows how much I'll remember?
这些年是我传播智慧的黄金年龄
These are my prime wisdom-giving years.
还有什么问题吗  卢克
You got any more questions, Luke?
只有一个
Just one --
我能尝一口吗
can I have a sip?
啤酒  当然  管他呢
The beer? Sure. What the hell.
太棒了  我第一次喝啤酒
Awesome. My first drink of beer.
我记得当初我第一次给米奇尔
I remember the day I gave Mitchell
喝啤酒的情景
his first taste of beer.
他面部扭曲地一直喝
He winced and carried on
就好像有人在从他的腿上取出一枚子弹
like someone was digging a bullet out of his leg.
我不忍心把菲尔的那一刻夺走
I couldn't take that moment away from Phil.
等等  等一下
Hang on. Wait a second.
让我看一下
Let me see that.
这啤酒不能喝了
No, this beer's skunked.
不好了
It's no good.
肯定是冰箱又出问题了
Damn fridge must be on the fritz again.
不是吧
Aw, man.
真的吗
Really?
不好意思  伙计
Sorry, buddy.
大概是时候打给你爸爸了  是吧
It's probably time to call your dad anyway, right?
好吧
Okay.
等一下
Wait a second.
我想给你些东西
I want to give you something.
但这些是你的
But those are yours.
如果不能给外孙些工具
What's a grandfather for
那要外公有什么用呢
if he can't give his grandson a couple of tools?
谢谢  外公
Thanks, grandpa.
好样的
Good job!
乔
Joe...
我知道你现在还只关心咪咪
I know you're all about the boobs right now,
但相信我
but trust me...
脖子才是重点
The neck.
别放手
Don't let go!
别担心  乔治・克鲁尼  我不会的
Don't worry, George Clooney, I won't!
你太帅了
You're too handsome!
注意远方太空垃圾来袭
Watch out for incoming space junk!
在哪
From where?
你的拉链开了
Your zipper's down!
真的吗
Oh, is it?
-是啊  -不好意思
- Yeah, it is. - Just... sorry.
安迪在这里干什么
What's Andy doing here?
他们在给他女朋友制作一个视频
They're making a video for his girlfriend.
是吗  叫什么  《太空蠢货》吗
Yeah? What's it called, "Dorks in space"?
其实挺感人的
Oh, it was actually sweet.
真奇怪
It's weird.
他有些地方很特别
There's something about him.
你懂我意思吗
You know what I mean?
懂  他跟老爸很像
Yeah, he's just like dad.
在太空里没人能听见你叫
In space, no one can hear you scream.
什么
What?!
在太空里没人能听见你叫
In space, no one can hear you scream!
我听不到你说什么
I can't hear you!
在太...
In spa--
我懂了
Oh, I just got it.
这个很逗  很逗
That's good. That's good.
谢谢
Thank you.
这确实很有原创性
There's no denying it is original,
但能看出波洛克对作者的影响
but you can see the influence of Pollock.
这个花样看似很随机
While the pattern seems haphazard and random,
但它也揭示了一种意图  一种目的
it belies a purposefulness -- a-an intentionality.
你知道吗  我觉得我看到的
You know, I think what I'm responding to
是相邻颜色的碰撞
is the clashing juxtaposition of color --
艳丽的黄和深色的背景
The bright yellow against the dark background.
就像黑暗世界中的一抹阳光
It's like a ray of sunshine in an otherwise bleak world.
但我不太同意
If I may take a contrary position...
我认为它代表着
...I think it speaks to the absurdity
人类愚蠢而枉然的尝试
and folly of human endeavor.
就好像我们对完美的徒劳追逐
Like our futile struggle for perfection.
我知道
I get it.
我的衣服沾上了芥末酱
I got mustard on my shirt.
别说了
Get over it.
虽然我们在开玩笑
I know we're joking,
但抛弃这点不谈
but all kidding aside,
这真的让我想起康丁斯基...
it really does remind me of Kandinsky's --